Brecht Devleesschauwer PhD DVM MVSc MStat

Head of Service Health Information

Sciensano, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health

brecht.devleesschauwer@sciensano.be | brechtdv.github.io

Rue Juliette Wytsman 14, 1050 Brussels, Belgium | +32 2 642 5035

Personal statement

The common goal of my research activities is to quantify the true impact of diseases and health inequalities, and to make model-based evaluations of prevention and control. Currently, I am coordinating the Belgian national burden of disease study and chairing the COST Action CA18218 "European Burden of Disease Network".

My research activities have led to over to 200 peer-reviewed scientific publications in national and international journals. My scientific expertise in burden assessment, risk assessment and health economics has been recognized through invitations to various national and international expert groups, including the Belgian Superior Health Council, the Belgian Food Safety Authority, and the World Health Organization.

Education

2015	PhD Veterinary Sciences; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE
	PhD Public Health; Université catholique de Louvain, Brussels, BE
2014	MSc Statistics; Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Louvain, BE
2010	MSc Veterinary Medicine; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE

2007 BSc Veterinary Medicine; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE

Employment

2022-	Head of Service; Sciensano, Brussels, BE
2018-	Visiting professor, risk analysis; UGent, Merelbeke, BE
2016-	Senior epidemiologist; Sciensano, Brussels, BE
2018-19	Visiting professor, advanced epidemiology; UCL, Brussels, BE
2016-18	Visiting professor, health economic evaluations; UCL, Brussels, BE
2015-16	Assistant scientist, global food safety and zoonoses; UF, Gainesville, USA
2015	Post-doctoral researcher; UGent, Merelbeke, BE
2013-14	Consultant; World Health Organization, Geneva, CH
2010-15	Doctoral researcher; UGent, Merelbeke, BE & UCL, Brussels, BE

Mentoring and supervision

10 PhD students · 55 MSc students · 8 BSc students

Scientific output

10 book chapters \cdot 221 peer-reviewed publications Google Scholar metrics: 14 517 citations \cdot h-index 46 \cdot i10-index 152